(213) 766-8700 kalkar@usc.edu Los Angeles, CA

# Aniruddha Kalkar

Linkedin/AniruddhaKalkar Github/AniruddhaKalkar aniruddhakalkar.github.io

Striving towards improving accessibility by solving challenges in vision-language domain as a diligent and ambitious engineer with 2+ years of software development experience and expertise in machine learning, Natural Language Processing, Computer Vision, Augmented Reality, Continuous Delivery and artificial intelligence.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### METRANS Transportation Center, USC Sol Price School of Public Policy

Jan 2022 - Present

Student Worker (Researcher)

Los Angeles

 Developed 3 game scenes for a game using Unity to educate pre-teenage and teenage kids about public transportation in LA County.

Textify AI Nov 2021- Dec 2021

Natural Language Processing Intern

Remote

- Optimized generative pre-trained (GPT-NEO) NLP model to auto-generate Natural language content for academic research proposals.
- Developed synonym suggestion enhancements to improve user sentence acceptance by 14.7%.

## Dassault Systèmes Solutions Lab

June 2019-Jul 2021

Pune, India

- Software Engineering Specialist
- Designed Revamped UI for the Lifecycle Management Service in the CI / CD Pipeline for the 3DEXPERIENCE platform to increase service usage across organization by approx 63%.
- Developed UI / UX for the CI / CD Pipeline for the 3DEXPERIENCE platform.
- Designed a prototype using NLP and Machine Learning to recommend QA testing scenarios using software requirements specification documents.
- Promoted to Software Engineering Specialist from R & D Development Associate position.

## **Tata Consultancy Services Research and Innovation**

Dec 2018-Apr 2019

New Delhi, India

- Research Intern
- Created Novel Metric to analyze Temporal Coherence of labels placed in videos for AR Applications.
- Introduced optical flow to give upto 50x Temporal Coherence improvement for the labels placed in the videos.
- Co-authored "SmartOverlays" published in WACV 2020.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

SmartOverlays: A Visual Saliency Driven Label Placement for Intelligent Human-Computer Interfaces
IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV).
Authors: Srinidhi Hegde, Jitendra Maurya, Aniruddha Kalkar, Ramya Hebbalaguppe

#### **PROJECTS**

## **UI Template Image to Code Generation**

Aug 2018-Apr 2019

- · Constructed a template UI code generating system from input screenshots or photos of GUIs
- Reduced code writing time by average 23.4 mins per web page.

#### Face sketch To Photo-Realistic Image Generation

Jan 2018-Jun 2018

- Spearheaded the creation of system to generate photo-realistic images from hand-drawn face sketches as well as predict age groups of people from sketches
- Achieved 77.65 % similarity with original image and 87.38% accuracy for age group prediction.

## **Driver Distraction Detection**

Aug 2017-Dec 2017

- Designed and created a driver distraction recognition and notification program based on a live video capture
- Attained 91.08% accuray for the 10 pre-determined distractions.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Computer Science (Artificial Intelligence), University of Southern California

Aug 2021-May 2023

GPA: 3.3 / 4.0

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering, Walchand College of Engineering GPA: 8.79 / 10.00

Aug 2015-May 2019

**TECHNICAL SKILLS** 

Languages
Libraries & Frameworks
Databases

Python, javascript, C/C++, Java, ASP.Net, HTML

TensorFlow, Pytorch, TFLearn, OpenCV, Keras, pymongo, NLTK, scikit-learn, matplotlib, Flask, Django

MySQL, MongoDB